Guide to the Manuscript Sheet Music Collection, circa 1800s-1900s RL.10068
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Manuscript Sheet Music collection
circa 1800s-1900s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.10068
0.3 Linear Feet 1 oversize folder; 20 pieces
Collection includes 20 pieces of collected manuscript sheet music, circa 1830s-1900s. The scores, which cover multiple genres, were most likely copied by hand from other sources.
Collection Overview
Collection includes 20 pieces of collected manuscript sheet music, circa 1830s-1900s. The scores, which cover multiple genres, were most likely copied by hand from other sources.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Manuscript Sheet Music collection was collected by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library over a number of years. The provenance of individual pieces is unknown.
Sheet music -- 19th century; Music -- Manuscripts; Sheet music; Rooke, W. M. (William Michael); Jones, Walter Howe; Howell, Charles T.; Shelley, Harry Rowe
- Manuscript sheet music
  - "My Boyhood Home," music by W.M. Rooke, circa 1830s (Box 1)
  - "Follow me 'ome," words by Rudyard Kipling; music by Harry Rowe Shelley, circa 1890s (Box 1)
  - "Song of the Souls of the Jollymariners," words by Rudyard Kipling; music by Harry Rowe Shelley, circa 1890s (Box 1)
  - Rondo Allegro [unidentified] (Box 1)
  - "O Softly Sleep my Baby Boy," music by C. Smith, circa 1818 (Box 1)
  - "My Mary! where each summer flower is blooming in its pride again..." [first line], undated (Box 1)
  - "Schotlisch," by Volckhart, undated (Box 1)
  - "Redwa Polka", undated (Box 1)
  - "Emilien Polka", circa 1870s (Box 1)
  - "Gravelona Waltz", circa 1870s (Box 1)
  - "Let the Merry Church Bells Ring", undated (Box 1)
  - "There is a Green Hill Far Away", circa 1880s-1890s (Box 1)
  - "Juanita: A Spanish Ballad," music by Mrs. Norton (Box 1)
  - "Baltimore Quick Step", circa 1820s-1860s (Box 1)
  - "College Song," words and music by Walter Howe Jones, circa 1900s (Box 1)
  - "Der Traum", undated (Box 1)
  - "Then the Sun Will Shine on Me," by Ashton Nichols, undated (Box 1)
  - "Looking unto God." Sacred Song for Alto or Baritone; words by Rev. Samuel Longfellow, music by Edwin Arthur Kraft, circa 1870s-1880s (Box 1)
  - "Green be your Fame Forever", undated (Box 1)
  - "By the Waters of Babylon," music by Charles T. Howell, circa 1890 (Box 1)